Uh, as you can see, uh, we have finished module 2.
And Uh, uh, crypto algorithm
authentication method that control modeling,
right? And then that's how people design the system or
You give them so that they can guarantee um the system secure
and this week and next week we will. Security,
which actually we use all of them from module.
And you can see there is a combination from module 2.
And then for network security guarantee the network design can be
secure. Uh-huh, yeah.
That, that's probably what happened with,
um, I don't know, with the internet issue,
but hopefully I'm keepinging clear. And then I'll check the
quality of the recording. If there's still some issue like this,
uh, I will probably have to make an offline one.
When I move my mouse. I, it doesn't work
properly. Oh, really?
I don't know, there there's a. There shouldn't be
a an issue. I'll try not move that one then.
I'll just uh use my arrow um from my keyboard up and
down, see whether there is some voice issue.
OK. OK, then. Um, so in,
in network security part, we will, we will see how do we use those
crypto, how do we design this authentication and use those
access control. Um, combine those methods,
and then we can make sure the network communication better than before.
Of course, those are people, how the experts,
they have designed their protocol, um, and to consider different
features to be added into our network protocol design so that we have a
better, uh, and a secure Um, network communication,
OK? And then we will, sorry. Sure, yeah.
And we have discussed this um TCP IP protocol suite
in our pre-le recording, um, because I know some people,
if you haven't learned computer system on computer networks before,
and you may have no idea about what TCP IP is,
um, then that's, that's included in the pre-elect recording.
And we discussed, um, and also I used the to,
to video from another professor. And then he has made some
popular YouTube video and he discussed how TCPIP uh
modeling uh was used in the 7 layer and then 4 layer and then
5 layers, right? And then you, we are actually in the lecture,
we just discussed, OK, for these layers,
there are these issues and how this issue can be fixed and how
people were trying to fix them, right? The different security issue.
OK? So these are the objectives for these two weeks.
Uh, I wish you understand the basic operation in our network
communication. And then there are some popular protocols.
Uh, we will actually focus on, um, the learning for
this, for this network. communication and we'll
discuss what's the problem with those protocols and how
those protocols were updated or uh upgraded,
right? To, to be a better one, right? And then people,
how people fix those issues existed in those protocols,
right? And then, yeah, so we, we will, we will discuss this
security issue layer by layer. And then we identify what's
the possible countermeasure for each layer,
right? So, this is a very um famous model
and when people think uh there are some issues there,
right, in those seven-layer model, but of course,
people now more talk about five layer, which is physical layer
from the very bottom, layer one. Right? And data link
layer, network layer, transport layer which is the 4th layer,
and on the top, the 3 layers in green, they are
recognized as one layer. We call them application layer,
right? So, in these different layers, Um,
people were trying to add this security goal to guarantee
this layer are more secure than before, right?
So you can see different security goal were added to those
layers so that we have something more secure in our internet
connection, in our internet communication.
OK? Um, And then, so, in this
week, we talked about the 1st 3 layers, from the bottom,
physical layer, link layer, and the network layer,
right? And then for next week, we will talk about transport layer and application layer.
We will discuss the main protocol in each layer and their problems and,
and how people have designed something new to fix those issues,
right? OK. So the very first one would be the physical layer,
OK, very bottom layer. And then, in the physical layer,
people have already had those transmission link shielding
to make it safer and also physical separation.
Or people can make equipment and cable redundancy um to make
the physical layer um better, OK. Always provide some alternative option
for people to fix the physical connection.
And of course, the service and the countersecurity.
So, number 3 and 4 are quite obvious, straightforward.
So we, we only focus on the number 1 and 2.
OK, for, yeah, to give a bit introduction how physical layer security were
guaranteed. And then the very first one is the trans uh
transmission link shielding. And in that shelling,
and when you look at the right top, the figure here,
right? So there's a center conductor which is copper
wire and then the signal will go through that copper,
cop copper wire. And then dielectric
um will wrap those copper, um, yeah, the,
the, the copper wire, right? Then signal,
yeah, will wrapped in, in those so that there won't be some
conduction from the very center to external.
And then there's a foil shell, OK? Those very uh like aluminum
um foil. And then that layer actually stops
the signal to be, um, to be leaked
from the center conductor because there is always electro
electromagnetic uh leaking, OK? Uh,
around the copper wire. And then that's why,
uh, that's what this foil shelding is doing.
It try to Prevent those electro uh
electromagnetic leaking from the signal transmission.
And then those braided shelding is actually trying to um
put another layer uh of those protections for the
electromagnetic leaking. And also, um,
it's protecting the external um
like break in to the center conductor.
Because when people try to use knife or the needle to go through
this, um, this transmission line, it's
very hard because it's protected by those braided shelding and the
foil shelding and also the dielectric, um,
those, those kind of protection, right? And then there's a rubber outside,
right? So, this is the actual transmission line shelding,
which is to keep this physical layers transmission better than
uh not having them, right? So, you can see all this
cable and switches, um, yeah, this cable were
doing this protection. And of course, sometimes,
When we, uh, when we wish to have, uh, prevent those
electromagnetic, uh, signal leaking, we can wrap the
whole signal in, uh, uh, in, in the
enclosed environment such as sometimes you would see,
um, if we have some transmission and we
wish those Wi Fi, those wireless communication signal wouldn't
be Um, going out and then you can put every equipment
in one. Um, in one. Room
which were wrapped by aluminum foil or some
iron material, right? So that actually can,
um, that is a similar thing to, to this at some shelling on
those transmission line. So which is to prevent those physical
layers, uh, disclosure. And another physical layer strategy
is this separation hub. So the picture just show you some
idea about how this hub or how this switch,
we call that separation switch, uh, looks like.
So it has this two internet connection and
to internet connection, and it, it also has this switch here in
the middle. Um, of those boards, right? So,
the switch can be switched left and right,
so that it allows either to connect to the internet,
and then if we don't want that internet connection,
we just switch to the right. So which makes sure this separation hub
only uh breaks, I mean, cut off those connection to the internet.
So we have 12 words here. One is internet,
which means external network. And intranet means internal
network. So, in a lot of cases, we actually wish to have this
kind of separation. The reason is,
um, there's a case study here, e-government,
right? In the, in this page. And you can see there's a,
sometimes confidential data in private network.
And we, we wish to protect this confidential data in this private network.
So, we don't do any direct connection from this private network
to internet, right? And then we always apply this
separation switch, OK, to put in the middle.
And then, the function of this separation.
Switch, OK. Very similar to isolation hub or air gap.
So, which is actually We talk about the function and the difference between this,
this separation hub and the firewall is the
firewall always put the connection as the first priority and it still
works on the security, but security is its second goal,
right? The connection is the first goal for firewall.
But for the separation hub, this physical separation switch,
and then their first priority is security.
Because they think that security is the very first goal and they have to
guarantee, so they physically separate the intranet and the internet,
which is external network and internal network,
right? So they physically separate. They only allow connection with the best
effort. So, they think it's 100% safe, they connect them um
through some way, right? Rather than direct connection.
Right? So that's the function, um, difference between firewall and
the physical separation switch. So in reality,
we use quite a lot, um, in a lot of very
high confidential case. For example, e-government or stock trading
system. So here is one case where you can see,
uh, we have the physical separation hub here in the bottom.
It's here, right? And then
It actually physically separate that internet and
internal server. We call that internet network,
right? And then when there's a um external data we
wish to transmit to the internet, we will go through this
physical switch and to the storage equipment first.
And then after that storage equipment, probably have done some
analysis and see there's no security alarm and then,
and then it will have another, um, the switch would
now connect this storage equipment to the internet.
And then, and then the data can be loaded to the intranet.
And then after that one, and then if there's something the internet
which, which to give to um the external network,
it will load the data back to the storage equipment,
OK? Do that way. And then after that one,
and then the network will be disconnected and then the switch hub,
the physical separation control system can then just allow the connection from
the storage equipment to the external network.
OK? So that doesn't allow direct connection between
the internet to the intranet. So, when you see in
the right top, and I have this um explanation
here. So, right. So when there's a harm to
internet, external server, right? And then it won't affect
the internet because there's a separation switch which physically separate
them, right? So we, this can protect those internet.
So, we, we use this physical separation to,
to, to do this physical layer security, um,
sometimes warranty. And we, we, we, we got to make sure,
um, To use that one. But of course, as I said,
this is putting that security at the first priority and then
only connect when, when some analysis is done and
then those connection is second priority in those networks.
OK. Um, and then we look at the data link layer,
which is the second layer. And then data link layer,
we can do, what we can do is to do an encryption.
And, and the wireless communication, and then that,
that WLAN means wireless uh Local Area Network and
SSID that we have those, um, Set,
uh, identifier, right? A service set identifier and then that,
yes, that is short for that name. So which is actually identifier with
some hotspot identifier, right? We, we always give a name for the hotspot or for the access
point, right? And then, so how do we guarantee um those
security settings? And then what are the difference between this
WEP and WPA and we have different options for our wireless
communication and data link layer strategy,
and we'll discuss that one. And also with uh address
spoof prevention. So there's some strategy as well,
um, to prevent the physical layer and, um,
I'm sorry, the data link layer and network layers.
address translation, like, I mean, IP address to MAC address,
right? And also, there's anti-sniffing uh techniques which we can
use to prevent this data link layer, um,
sniffing issue. OK. So firstly, look at
this uh data encryption. Um, so data
link layer encryption means we can encrypt the data at the link layer,
OK? And then, which I mean, OK, so this is
uh, the bottom one is a link layer
encryption. And the top one is uh end to end
encryption. So then you can see in the end to end encryption,
we can still see those header and the trailer information,
right? 1010 and 1011. So those are the header and
trailer information which normally uh were attached to the original signal.
So you can imagine your email, right? When you send an email to,
to a receiver. And your email will be attached to,
uh, will be attached by some header information.
For example, where the email was from, from which IP
address. And the destination is where, right?
So those kind of information will be attached to this email.
We call them header and trailer and information,
right? So, we, we, we have them. And you can imagine whether your email,
OK? We can encrypt in data link layer, which is the bottom solution,
right? We encrypt the whole message where you can't see those
header and the trailer information anymore.
Of course, the whole email will also be protected,
right? So that's the data link layer encryption option.
Um, but in this way, that also means
When your email was forward from one router to another
router, And then that router and maybe the next switch,
right? We normally have the switch at the second layer uh device to
forward your um whole package to the next switch,
right? So the switch needs to read your uh header and the
trailer information so that switch knows where this email was from.
And then the switch needs to decrypt the whole encrypted
package. To read, to be able to read the header and trailer information,
right? In that case, the switch got to have a decryption key,
right? Decryption key. And then if we, every,
every hop in the middle, the switch, every switch needs to read.
Of course, in the transmission line, the encrypted message may be safe,
right? However, the switch got to be able to decrypt the
message and then encrypt it again, and then Trust me to the
next hope. But in that way, it means. In
those switch place, the switch has access to your
email address, uh email content which uh was in
plain text, right? So because he can decrypt your message,
then that makes your email not safe, right?
Because the, the encryption at link layer um encrypt
the header and trailer information but also encrypt your message,
your email. But, but that switch in the middle got to
decrypt that each packet at each switch,
right? And then, that makes it not so safe.
And then uh people say, say, OK, we can also consider end to end encryption,
which means at higher layer, you can imagine at your application
layer, OK? When you write your email, and when you do end to
end encryption, you just encrypt your email itself by
Some, um. Like triple desk. OK. You have a key and you just do
a simple command, and you encrypt your email into a ciphertext,
and then you send to your, uh, to, to send to the internet,
right? And in that way, your message itself is encrypted.
We call that. Uh, application layer encryption,
right? And then, Of course, if we can have both,
input the message and header and the trailer information attached,
and then we encrypt again, right, we encrypt it 2 times.
And that makes your transmission really safe.
Even if in the middle, the switch decrypt.
Uh, to read the header and trailer information,
the switch still doesn't get access to the plain text of your email.
Because email itself, the message in the very top here,
and It has been encrypted, right? So
those header information when it goes to transport layer,
network layer, link layer, and a different header were added.
And in the link layer, those three header can also be,
uh, together with the ciphertext together would be encrypted again.
So that's some better strategy we can have during our
transmission, right? Um, of course, every
strategy sometimes has different cost that we have to consider.
Um, yeah. So, that's the data
encryption option for our data link layer.
And then for the wire wireless communication,
OK? Uh, as we said, uh, the wireless communication,
this also belongs to data link layer things.
We put it here. And then, with wireless communication,
right? And our phone can set ourselves to be a hotspot,
right? And your home router can set itself to provide service to
a lot of devices, right? And there's also some access point.
Um, for example, in Griffiths campus, there are a lot of
different, uh, Wi Fi access points allowing you to connect through Griffith's
Wi Fi. Right? So, for all these access point,
we have to have a unique service set identifier.
We normally call the SSID number. Right?
And then this number uh can be 32 characters at the most,
right? And should be a unique number which was
recognizable by those different devices,
right? Sometimes we call that, you can see the airport Wi Fi,
1, airport Wi Fi, 2, and you got to recognize which one is the right one to
access, right? And then, there are some options for this.
Hotspot or access point, right? And you can,
when you set up, you can allow to process this Wi
Fi, oh sorry, this SSID by default.
Which means, uh, you just allow them to broadcast them,
right? And make this setting here. Um,
Right? So you, you allow them to broadcast themselves
and say, OK, I'm here, I'm providing this service.
This is my SSID if you want to connect me and you can try to provide the
right, like keywords, right? And password and you can connect through me.
And, so that's a broadcasting SSID. Normally,
the SSID um, is broadcasted uh by
default, right? Of course, you can, uh, hide SSID.
And you think, OK, you always let all people know there's a service here,
which is not safe. You try to hide your SSID.
But sometimes this doesn't keep you, uh,
access points safer. Because if there were some devices,
um, Connected to you before and then they will,
next time they still can find you, and then still can um connect through you,
um, I mean, automatically. And you can see there's some option like this,
OK, in the right. Bottom corner.
There's some option, uh, of course, by clicking this option doesn't put your network,
uh, very safe, but there is some option by default if you don't
carefully untick them. So it allows the connection,
even if the network is not broadcasting,
if there's some devices Connected to you before and then they can still
uh connect through you, right? So, with this hiding
SSID doesn't mean you're making your um access point very
safe because maybe there was some default setting like this,
and then there was still some uh devices able to connect to
you, OK? Uh, by default automatically, right?
And then, uh, with this SSID setting, and we probably
should consider those, um, default
SSID set by manufacturer should be changed because those
default names can be recognized by attackers.
And also, the attacker can then Um, analyze,
OK, through the SSID default names to analyze your router's make
and model information, right? And, and there's a default
password as well, normally kept online and then,
or sometimes kept by a manufacturer. And then those attacker can
guess uh if you haven't changed your key,
right? And then those key, automatic key can be stolen or can be uh
grabbed by those attacker automatically through simple
analysis, which is why People should never
use default password set up by the router.
You should change them, right? And when you change them,
also make sure your key, OK, in this right bottom picture.
Should be really long and longer than 13 at
least, or sometimes 20, the longer the better,
right? More combination put you safer as well.
And then you use a default one. I think in,
in our 1 weeks, um I think week 6, right?
Activity, you've already seen those default passwords can be just uh
seen from online, from some company and they just keep them,
right? And then there are also some options for you to choose about the
security type and the encryption type. And I've put one error
uh from down to the top and very top one would be the
most secure one. And then least secure one would be open network,
of course, from 1 to 6, right? The first one gives you the top
security level. Um, which is the option you should choose.
Which means the security type should be WP WPA2.
Um, and then never choose WEP, right? like
number 5. And there are options here. You can see from your drop-down box,
when you set up your own home router, your home router gives you this option.
OK, like this. This strong box. And you
can see those WEP, WPA and
WPA2, right? And you're using that one for your personal,
uh, home, and you can choose WPA 2, personal,
um, right, or, or WPA2
enterprise, right? So that's the option.
We should have. And then the incurring type is AES.
You, if you, if you use your drop-down box in your home router,
you would be able to see triple DES, DES,
AES. OK, these options. Among these three options,
you know that AES is faster than triple DES and also more
secure than triple DES and the DES, right?
So that's the option we should choose. Uh,
we should set for our home router. That actually gives
our home router, um, all the traffic through our home
router a very secured protection, right?
If we're choosing some weaker protocol and a weak encryption
type, and that actually can be easily broken
by Those attacker because those have been
proven to have some security flaw, right?
Those protocol and those encryption type,
right? OK. So, this is how we, how we should set up our home
router to make it safer. And then, of course,
something um extend here is just to, to,
just about some practice thing. And then with everyone,
everyone probably has used this public Wi Fi hotspot,
right? So when we use this hotspot, um, from
our computer, we should enable firewall.
And there's some network setting in our computer.
We should turn on the Windows firewall, uh,
and we should turn on the sharing, and you should be able to see a screenshot
like my one here in the right bottom corner.
And then there's turn off option for your networks discovery,
for your file and the printer sharing, and then for your public folder sharing,
you should turn off of them if you are using a public Wi Fi hotspot.
And you should use the right public Wi Fi connection.
Always check the SSID. Make sure you're using a
legitimate official one to connect. Because there are
many cases in the airport. I actually, I have um seen one
before. Airport. Some people, they can just pretend their
phone to be the, or they just use some access point,
um, to be a hotspot and then they name their hotspot.
Airport, Wi Fi, free, right? So just name that
one, and then if you accidentally connect to the
internet through their hotspot, which means every packet you're sending from your
phone is through their hotspot, and they can sniff every packet,
right? They can then try analyze if you happen to use your credit card to pay
something, they can try to grab those information from your traffic
flow, right? Which is why when we try to connect the public Wi Fi,
you got to make sure you are using an official connection.
And always use HTPS NSL. That gives you
a better uh protection on your laptop. Because in our internet setting,
we have this option here. So, browser connection,
you can see here, right? And it has always used
HTPS. So you do not allow any other um
HTTP connection. Um, in our, um,
uh, sorry, uh, uh, workshop, uh, sniffing,
um, activity this week, you will see why HTPS is
better than HTP. And then When we
have to use public Wi Fi to do an online transaction or
bank service, we got to make sure we use
the private. VPN first. OK? We connect through
the VPN first and then we go to the bank site to do online transaction.
Otherwise, this, OK, using public Wi Fi to do bank
transaction always put yourself at a huge risk,
right? And then disabled Wi Fi when not in use.
If you don't want um any Wi Fi connection,
you think Wi Fi connection is not safe and just use your mobile network connection.
I use 6G and that's better actually. And then just disable your Wi Fi.
Because otherwise, you're always are broadcasting message and try to connect with some local
um available access point. And that actually gives your
um neighbor and any attacker nearby,
um, some message, oh, this device appears in this zone and then try
to connect through some Um, access point.
So, and if you don't want to appear or attract their eye and you just uh
disable your Wi Fi, right? And there are a lot of,
uh several other, you can disable your Bluetooth,
you can disable your an NFC um near field communication
and all that kind of uh protocol, you can disable them from your
local phone. And then keep your Windows antivirus software
updated and use the best judgment. With this best judgment,
I mean, um, when you're in a coffee shop,
and if you Talk to their manager, you know how they set up
their home router, their, their public uh Wi Fi router.
And they, they've chosen WPA2 and AES and you know they
set up their router properly. Otherwise,
OK, if they're using a weak combination and that actually put every customer who is
using their Wi Fi at risk, right? OK.
And then with the link layer, we also have this um MAC address
and IP address translation protocol, OK?
Which actually means when we have some message to a computer in this
local network, right? There's an ARP protocol which
translates from the IP address. To McAddress.
MACAddresses, their physical, uh, unique,
um, universally, a universally, um, unique address,
right? So every device has a MAC address.
And then they translate from IP address to that,
um, MAC address. And then, and then this computer would respond to that IP.
Request and then, and then the computer on the top would just,
uh, OK, new, oh, here is a device which
has this MAC address, which has been allocated this IP address.
So IP will be translated to a particular MAC address and you can see from
this computer, from this page. Yeah. And there's a
mapping, um, 1 to 1 mapping translation,
uh, which was added dynamically because the
computer here is always learning from all the messages and then
he will keep a record who is who, who has this IP address,
uh, which is that Mac computer. That MAC address has this
IP address. So it has all this table maintained.
And then, this protocol uh maintains such a table so that it
can dive uh it can forward the message to the right computer.
And now you can imagine if there's a computer who is
a hacker, and then he doesn't behave well.
So he can always um cheat,
right, on those, on those Mac address and he would tell the
other computer the wrong message. And if this record is
added to this record table, and which actually could cause trouble
and where the message won't go to the right computer,
will go to the fake computer, right? So,
Mm. Thanks for the sharing, uh, Tricia. So,
that's some way people try to fix this issue with
ARP protocol. And of course, we can always try maintain
a correct ARP record table, and we can use a fixed ARP table
but doesn't offer flexibility. And, but with a fixed one,
and no one can replace original uh record,
right? Or people thinking about that we don't use this ARP anymore
and then those are some, some strategy people are thinking about this ARP
issue. And then, are there any better way,
right? And then there are always some, something,
um, the people are considering to, to do better in this
ARP uh translation. And another thing about
sniffing. You can think um the sniffing is actually
a program, right? And then that can monitor and analyze network
traffic. And the, it can be used for good purpose because people
can detect the bottleneck and can detect the problems in the
network transmission. And, however, it can also be used by bad
people and try to analyze the traffic and try to intercept and uh steal
some information and valuable, right? So,
um, We can always diagnose how and
also whether there's a sniffing uh happening,
right? And of course, anyone can sniff. Sometimes they sniff
for good purpose. For example, the ISP which means internet
service providers such as Telstra, Optus,
and then they can also sniff, right? So they are internet service provider.
And then the government can also sniff because it sometimes is put surveillance
on all traffic flow. And then they also try to do
some capacity plan at a very high level,
right? And those advertisement um company also sniff,
right? And they do some analysis, and the bad guy can also sniff and then
try to steal useful information. And this is a sniffer
tool, uh, which can, uh, identify whether
sniff, OK, uh, sniffing tool, and then there are also anti-sniffing tool,
right? So, the wild shark is a very, uh,
famous free tool which allows everyone to use and the
sniff, the packets. So, we will use wild shark
in our workshop and then you, you can see how to use wild shark to sniff to
analyze the packets. And then there, of course,
also some anti, anti-sniffing tool, right?
And then, then people can identify and stop them.
And this is just one interface and you will see that one,
how to use this one in our workshop. OK?
And then in the one layer. Above which is network layer.
OK? So there are a lot of vulnerability as well in this network layer.
The IP address is what normally used in network layer,
right? It's kind of like the post address,
right? So we have unique, uh global unique IP
address given to um this internet. And then the,
and then the router or sometimes the transmission and
They know how to send your message to a different IP address.
It's just like sending the mail and we send to a particular,
uh, Location, right? And which has a city name,
which has a post, postcode, right? Which represented
a city or a specific uh specific suburb,
right? And the IP address same thing and which happens in this network layer and the
people recognize that um package to be sent to either
America or a different country, right? So those IP address has
those kind of connection to the physical location,
right? And then, we have this IP address a lot of issue,
uh, happening in this layer, and we'll mainly talk about routing table vulnerability and
IP address vulnerability. Firstly, about routing table.
And because routing table always uh dynamic learning table um
during the transmission. And then, there are a lot of
voting algorithm um in this transmission.
And sometimes, um, when Uh, attack,
OK? Uh, launches to a specific router, OK,
in the middle, and that can cause DOS attack.
We call that denial of service attack because,
um, that router doesn't respond and, uh,
or some server, which is in the end of the,
the, the internet on the other end and it doesn't respond.
So that causes a denial of service. And so that's what we call
DOS attack. So when there's a routing, a router
in the middle which has been attacked and which just doesn't work
properly with forwarding your packets and the router can just uh
stop working and then can cut off the the route
to, from the source to the destination, right?
So there can be this kind of attack to a router.
And then it can be a poisoned table, which means some
phase routing records were um given
to this router and the router cannot do a proper routing
for a packet, OK, to the destination. So there are some forged
routing records. And then there can be a flooding table,
which means the the routing table has been flooded with fake records,
and then there's no proper routing could happen during that.
And then sometimes a valid routing records will be,
um, will be learned, but because the, the
fake records has, has been flooded in that routing table,
so the routing table doesn't Doesn't learn a new item and doesn't do
a proper routing. So we call that flooding table and can happen to the routing
table. And also we can have routing path spoof.
Um, normally, the routing algorithm are calculating the short,
shortest path. To save time, right? To, to,
to, to shorten the delay in communication.
But the shortest path can be um attacked and
cheated. OK, right? So that short routing path spoofing can happen.
And QS um we here in this here.
QS first path is to A QS means quality of
service. So, which, OK, in the routing different algorithm,
we can calculate shortest path, we can calculate the quality of service best,
which is the best reliable path, right? But that path can be
calculated, however, The algorithm could go wrong and then there can be
some spoofing happening about my own service,
right? And then the other router thought this router uh works
better than the other one. And then, so they go through.
This router rather than the other one. So then this cheating happens and then the
routing path is spoofed again, right? So then finally,
it can result in poor routing and slow routing,
and very high expensive route uh expensive routing,
right? So, these are the routing tables issue.
And another issue, very, very famous vulnerability is
address issue with IP address. And then,
with IP address, the issue is because there's no authentication for IP
address user. Uh, for example, when we have to use uh uh a SIM
card for our phone, right? We have to register our name and our address,
email, our ID. So that they know, OK, this person has this
phone number, right? So that phone number belongs to a particular ID.
However, online, our computer were given an IP
address. That IP address doesn't need to,
doesn't need you to um present your ID to be given
to you. Which is why when something happened,
And then the person can claim, oh, that's not my IP and then there's no proof,
right? Sometimes, because there's no authentication uh needed for IP
use. And then that actually caused a lot of issues.
Um, the fake I address, um, yeah. So,
people will sometimes they, they, they, they load something to the internet and then
there's no connection, uh, from that IP to their
ID information. So people can never, uh,
know who did that, right? Because there's no authentication here.
And then, um, also some other issues such as the fake
address text, block uh uh text. Uh, which means,
OK, this different case can happen. So,
for example, if you have a particular IP and attacker
Works in the same domain. And then attacker can set up
their computer to use exactly the same IP address as you,
right? And then, well, they don't know the IP they just uh
know there are some particular IP will be allocated in this network.
And so they just uh set up their own IP address to be something which can
uh cause conflicts in the local network.
And then that makes the communication wouldn't be properly going on,
right? So the um right message won't go to the actual
Computer which has that conflicting IP address,
right? So, it will stop the right user receiving packets.
And also, that can also stop the communication to the user
with the same IP. And then you can also think about when your attacker's
IP is configured the same as the router's IP,
then all the communication between the router and the All
nodes within the same subnet or same network will be blocked because
the router's IP uh has some conflicts with attacker's IP
address. And then there's also fake release attack,
fake release attack here in the DHCP protocol.
DHCP protocol is managing to grab back
the Uh, idle IP address, which is not used by other people
and it will, um, dynamically, um, collect them and
then allocate to the new computer. And then now you can think
if we have fake release uh given a message
going around and this DHCP protocol thinks,
oh, this IP address is released, so it will just allocate to a new computer.
But that can also cause conflicts because we can't have the two same IP
working properly in the same subnet, OK,
same small network. Right? So, That fake release attack can
happen, OK, to this dynamic host of configuration protocol.
And then there's also flooding, ICMP flooding issue and uh we will
try to simulating this kind of flooding,
uh, in, in our workshop. And then, of course,
that happens like this. So, um,
ICMP is a protocol which can check whether the other computer
is alive or is working online, uh, or not,
right? So when they send a, uh, checking message,
and then the other computer can just reply to this computer,
oh I'm alive, I'm working online right now.
So, the computer, between the computer and they know,
they knew the status. So the ICMP is doing that.
So then you can imagine the attacker can send a lot of
checking message to. And a bunch of computers,
and a bunch of computers. And then with a fake IP address.
And then when the other computer try to respond to this source
IP address, where This request message will
put a wrong victim's IP address. And then so this bunch of
computer wouldn't reply to this attacker.
They would all reply to the victim's IP address,
right? So all message will come to this victim.
We call that flooding. Right? This flooding attack can make this
vic uh victim's computer down, OK, not responding to any other
messages. If this victim is a server, and the server will definitely
um not be able to respond to other customer's request,
right? So this is how uh we can launch this denial of
service attack to a server through ICMP flooding
attacks. We, we also call that Smurf attacks.
Uh That can cause the, the denial of service.
So I'll just keep going with this recording.
And if you are busy and please feel free to leave and because we started a
bit late due to the network issue, I'll keep this,
um, just my last page. Um, so, there are some
countermeasure in this network layer. And of course,
we have the protocol itself which try to fix all this issue.
And we call that IPV4 V6, OK?
IPV6 is a new Um, protoc design suit, which was
different from IPV4 and which has used a different lengths of IP
address in IPV 6, right? But IPV6 is a new
next generation IP protocol where our current
equipment still, not every type of equipment supports
IPV 6, which is why we're still using IPV 4.
And we need something extra to Um, fix the
issue in IPV4, which is why we have IPsec,
OK? Which is, uh, um, Fixing
protocol suit to fix IPV4. Of course, people were trying to
upgrade to IPV 6, but that's not happening in probably the next 10
years, which is why, um, yeah, IPV 6 is there already,
but not every equipment can support and uh so that we,
people are still using IPEC to fix some issue in IPV 4.
That's from the protocol, uh, point of view to fix this security issue.
But then, another strategy we can have is to uh disable
ICMP because a lot of surveys, they actually disable ICMP.
They just, they don't respond to, um, to the,
to the um ICMP request to check whether they are alive.
They just don't respond. And then they can also do IP filtering.
So, through some uh firewall, OK, they can do
IP filtering and through some special system like,
um, like, um, IPS IDS, this kind of intrusion detection
system, and they also try to filter out some IP address.
They think those IP were not legitimate and they were just,
um, behaving badly. So they just filled out those IP of course,
that can work efficiently. And another way is to uh
assign some private address for local network uh by using this kind of
server, we call that NAT server, uh, which is Network Address
Translation server. And this is the one,
and then it will try to protect internal privacy.
So then you can imagine when there's a request from Computer C
to web server, and then internally, it has an
IP address. But this IP address is just used for internal
purpose. It won't present this internal IP address to external that
actually provide some privacy for this. Computers within this
internal network. And then, NAT server in the middle
will translate and will forward any message from computer CAB,
OK, this com different computer to the external um web
server. And also from the web server, the message when it's sent
back, this NAT because it's a network address translate,
translator, it will, um, Come to find the right computer
and forward them to the right computer. This is NAT server.
It is doing this. OK. So that's actually all what we can do
in the network layer to protect um the network layer
um to be better, right? So we'll discuss more next week,
um, how the other layer can work, right?
Um, and then, yeah, so that's all for today.
Thank you. Uh, we'll move to the transport layer and other solutions,
and we'll talk about the protocol solution as well.
OK? So which covers those different layers design.
OK. Thank you for all.
I'll see you next time.